onemainfinancial.com 2019-06-11

# Privacy Policy - OneMain Financial

This OneMain privacy policy ("Privacy Policy") describes our practices about information collected about you when you visit the Site. 

"Site" means all websites including www.onemainfinancial.com, interactive features, widgets, plug-ins, applications, content, downloads and other electronic services maintained by any of the OneMain or OneMain Financial family of companies. 

“we,” “us,” “our,” or “OneMain,” as used on this Site, mean the OneMain and OneMain Financial family of companies. 

“you” or “your” mean you as an individual and, if you are an employee or representative of another person or entity, such person or entity. 

Please review the Terms of Use. The Terms of Use governs your use of the Site. By using the Site, you agree to this Privacy Policy and the Terms of Use. You also agree to our collection, use, disclosure and storage of your information as described by this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, do not provide us with any Personal Information and do not use this Site. 

This Privacy Policy does not apply to the following. 

  * Data we get from third parties, unless we combine such data with Personal Information (defined below) that we have collected under this Privacy Policy.
  * Our data collection activities offline or outside of the Site (unless otherwise stated below).
  * The data practices of third parties that may interact with the Site, such as social media sites and websites where we advertise.

## What Type of Information do we Collect?

 _Non-Personal Information._

We and our third-party service providers may use tracking technologies. These technologies store or collect certain information when you visit or interact with the Site (“Usage Information”). This Usage Information may be stored or accessed using technologies that may be downloaded to your computer, browser, laptop, tablet, mobile phone or other device (a “Device”) when you visit or interact with the Site. This Usage Information may include:

  * Your IP address, UDID or other unique identifier (“Device Identifier”). A Device Identifier is a number that is automatically assigned to your Device, and our systems identify your Device by its Device Identifier.
  * Your Device functionality (such as browser, operating system, hardware, and mobile network information).
  * The areas within the Site that you visit and what you do there, such as remembering you and your preferences, and the pages, screens, or other displays of information you looked at.
  * Your Device location.
  * Your Device characteristics.
  * Other Device data, such as the time of day, date, length of your visit(s), frequency of your visits, and patterns of use among other information.
  * Domain name you use to access the Internet and other information obtained from Web page headers (i.e., type of Device and type and version of web browser).
  * Internet address from which you linked to the Site.
  * Information contained in or relating to any communication that you send to us or sent through the Site, such as the content of the communication and metadata associated with it.

 _Personal Information._

On the Site, we may ask you for information that identifies you personally (“Personal Information”) such as: 

  * Full name.
  * Date of birth.
  * Relationship status.
  * Home address and telephone number.
  * Email address.
  * Social security number.
  * Driver's license number.
  * Bank account and/or payment card information.
  * Employment information.
  * Information about your assets, debts and income.
  * Username.
  * Password.

We may collect Personal Information through many forms and in many places on the Site. This may include if you apply for a loan, through "contact us" forms, or when you interact with the Site. 

Please see our Privacy Notice for an explanation of how we collect, use and share Personal Information. It also explains how you can limit the use and sharing of your Personal Information. We provide this notice to all of our customers. 

## How do we use Collected Information?

We and our service providers may use your information that is covered by this Privacy Policy: 

  * To process transactions such as your loan application. 
  * To underwrite your loan. 
  * To provide you with information such as to send you electronic newsletters. 
  * To provide you with ads on behalf of us or third parties, such as to let you know about new products, services or upcoming events. 
  * To verify your identity. 
  * To prevent fraud. 
  * To create your account. 
  * To communicate with you about your transactions, such as to provide customer support. 
  * To offer you products and services. 
  * To send monthly statements, service and collect amounts you owe. 
  * So you can take part in many of the Site’s features, such as to enable you to take part in online entry sweepstakes, contests or other promotions. 
  * To customize your experience on the Site or to serve you with specific content or ads that are relevant to you. 
  * To improve the Site, our marketing and our Site offerings. 
  * For internal business purposes. 
  * For other purposes that are disclosed at the time you provide your information or otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy. 
  * To the extent necessary to enforce the Terms of Use. 

## How about Cookies, Web Beacons and other Tracking Technologies?

We use tracking technologies on the Site. This includes Cookies and Web Beacons. Cookies and Web Beacons collect and store Usage Information. A “Cookie” is a small file containing letters, numbers and symbols. A Cookie stores information about the user or records the user’s browsing activity. Your Device’s hard drive stores Cookies. A “Web Beacon” is an electronic image (1x1.gif) located within a certain web page. A Web Beacon allows the Site to record the simple actions of the user opening the page. Cookies, Web Beacons, and other tracking technologies (e.g., HTML5 and Flash local storage, embedded scripts, and e-tags/cache browsers) may be active on the Site. We may use other tracking technologies in connection with the Site. 

We may send tracking technologies to your Device when you visit the Site, or other sites where our ads appear. We may send tracking technologies for different purposes, such as: 

  * To allow you to use and access the Site. 
  * To monitor your experience on the Site. 
  * To allow us to improve the Site. 
  * To improve security on the Site. 
  * For identity verification and fraud prevention. 
  * To analyze traffic and transactions on the Site. 
  * Keeping track of your preferences, such as the presentation of content on the Site. 
  * To market our products and services, such as delivering content based on how you interact with the Site. 

We may also work with data providers who collect web log data from you. Web log data may include your IP address and information about your browser or operating system. We may place a data provider’s cookie that recognizes your browser and enables you to receive customized ads or content. These cookies contain no personally identifiable information. They may contain or reflect demographic or other data about your interests in a de-identified form. The information in these cookies may link to data you gave us. This may include your name, postal address or email. We may share this data with a data provider in hashed or encrypted form. To opt out of these data provider cookies, please go to the Digital Advertising Alliance (“DAA”) website at <http://www.aboutads.info/choices>. 

We also use depersonalized aggregated Usage Information to improve the performance of the Site. This information may be provided to other companies to help us with this. These other companies may include third-party advertisers, analytics providers, and other service providers. This information can’t be used to identify you. 

Your browser should allow you to manage tracking technologies. If your browser’s settings are too strict, you may not be able to use all of the features of the Site. 

You may enter the Site from a third-party site, such as a search engine or referral site. Those sites may use tracking technologies to track their own site performance. You must review the privacy policy of each third-party site to know what information about you they collect and how they use it. 

## How about Interactions with Third-Party Services?

The Site may include functions that allow interactions between the Site and a third-party web site or application. The functions may involve the third-party operator providing certain information including Personal Information, to us. For example, if you click on social media icons on the Site (such as for Facebook, Twitter or Instagram), we may have access to your Personal Information you provided on those third-party sites or applications. If so, we will treat it as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy. We may also provide third-party sites’ interfaces or links on the Site so you can send a message from the Site. For example, we may use third parties to facilitate emails, tweets or Facebook postings. These third parties may keep information used or provided in those messages or activities. Their practices are not subject to our Privacy Policy. We may not control or have access to your communications through these third parties. When you use third-party sites or services, you are using their services and not ours. We are not responsible for their practices. You should review the third parties’ privacy policies before using third-party tools on the Site. 

## How about Advertising?

The Site collects data about your activities online. We may use it to provide advertising tailored to your interests. We may use third parties such as network advertisers and ad exchanges to serve ads across the Internet. We may use third-party analytics service providers to test and provide us and third parties with information about the use of these ads on third-party websites and viewing of ads and of our content. Third parties may offer you a choice about having your information collected for that purpose. This section of the privacy policy provides details and explains how to make that choice. 

You may see certain ads on other third-party websites and services on the Internet. This is because we take part in advertising networks administered by third parties. These networks collect information about your online activities across third-party websites such as through the use of the tracking technologies. They use this information to tailor ads to your interests. The information they collect includes information about your visits to the Site, such as the pages you viewed. These third-party tracking technologies may (a) help deliver ads to you that you might be interested in; (b) keep you from seeing the same ads too many times; and (c) understand the usefulness to you of the ads that you receive. You agree that associated technology may access and use your Device. You agree that it may set or change settings on your Device for the associated operations. 

This collection and ad targeting happens both on the Site and on third-party websites that take part in the ad network. This helps us track the effectiveness of our marketing efforts. For example, third-party service providers, like Google, may show you our ads on the Internet. Third-party vendors, like Google, use tracking technologies to serve ads after a user visits the Site. The tracking technologies say “This person visited this page, so show them ads relating to that page.” You may opt out of Google’s use of cookies by visiting the Google advertising opt-out page <https://www.google.com/settings/u/0/ads/authenticated?hl=en>. We are not responsible for any third parties’ opt-out options. 

## Google Analytics Advertising Features.

We use these Google Analytics advertising features: 

  * Remarketing with Google Analytics. 
  * Google Display Network Impression Reporting. 
  * Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting. 
  * Integrated services that need Google Analytics to collect data via advertising cookies and anonymous identifiers. 

Service providers may set and access their own tracking technologies on your Device. They may collect or have access to information about you, which may include Personal Information. For example, on the Site, Google will collect, store, and use this information to report on how you use the Site. You can opt out of the Google Analytics Advertising Features through their Ads Settings or any other available means. You can find Google Analytics’ opt outs at: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>. 

We do not control third parties' collection or use of your information to show you interest-based advertising. These third parties may allow you to choose not to have your information collected or used in this way. You can opt out of getting targeted ads from members of the Network Advertising Initiative ("NAI"). You may do this by visiting the NAI's website at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices>. You may also be able to opt out of getting third-party behavioral ads. You may do this by visiting the DAA website at [http://www.aboutads.info/choices](http://www.aboutads.info/choices/). We are not a member of NAI or DAA. 

We are not responsible for any third parties’ opt-out options. 

## How do we Share Information?

We may share non-Personal Information with third parties. This may include aggregated user statistics. We may share your Device Identifiers with third parties with data related to you and your activities. 

Our Privacy Notice explains what Personal Information we may share with third parties. 

We may also share the information we collect about you as follows:

  * For any purpose you expressly consent to. 
  * To protect or enforce our rights or the rights or safety of others. 
  * As allowed or required by applicable law, regulation, subpoenas, governmental requests or legal process. 
  * In connection with a merger, acquisition, restructuring, asset transfer, or other operational or corporate changes to our company, such as any due diligence process. 
  * For joint marketing with other companies. 
  * To our parent, subsidiaries and affiliates. 
  * To non-affiliates for their marketing purposes. 
  * To our third-party service providers who may use shared information in accordance with this Privacy Policy and to provide the services we request. We may use third-party service providers to perform certain services for us or the Site, such as: 
    * To assist us in Site operations. 
    * To process your transaction and maintain your account. 
    * To manage a database of customer information. 
    * Hosting the Site. 
    * Designing and/or operating the Site’s features. 
    * Tracking the Site’s activities and analytics. 
    * Enabling us to send you special offers or perform other administrative services. 
    * Other services that assist us in maximizing our business potential. 
  * We may give these service providers access to user information, such as Device Identifiers and Personal Information, to carry out the services they are performing for you or for us. 

## Can I Confirm that the Information OneMain collects is Correct or Make Changes to my Information?

Keeping your account information accurate and up to date is very important. You can make certain changes by logging into account management on the Site. If you cannot make changes online, or if you want to request changes offline, please contact us at the following phone number or postal address. 

1-800-742-5465 

OneMain 

P.O. Box 3662 

Evansville, IN 47735-3662 

## How is my Personal Information Protected?

To protect your Personal Information from unauthorized access and use, we use security measures that comply with federal law. These measures include computer safeguards and secured files and buildings. No data transmission over the Internet, mobile networks, wireless transmission or electronic storage of information is 100% secure. 

## Am I Protected when Linking from the Site to other sites?

This Privacy Policy is for customers and visitors, and only applies to this Site. This Site only includes its home page and pages hereunder operated by OneMain. This Privacy Policy does not apply to any linked site or any third-party site. You must review the privacy policy of such third-party sites to know what information about you is collected and how it is used. 

## Online Tracking and do not Track Disclosures.

Third parties use tracking technologies with the Site. This may include the collection of information about your online activities. We may not control those tracking technologies. We are not responsible for those tracking technologies. You consent to encountering third-party tracking technologies when using the Site. You accept that this Privacy Policy does not apply to the tracking technologies or practices of such third parties. 

Third parties that have content embedded on the Site may set Cookies on a user’s browser. They may also get information that a web browser visited a OneMain website from a certain IP address. 

Other third parties are making or have made signals or other mechanisms for consumer choices about the collection of information about a consumer’s online activities. We do not track or take any action on these signals or other mechanisms. We do not allow third parties to collect Personal Information about a user’s online activities when that user uses the Site, service or applications. 

## How about Information I Disclose Publicly or to Others?

  *  _User Content and Public Information._ The Site or the Program site (as referred to in **“OneMain Rewards Program”** below) may allow you to submit ideas, photographs, video, pictures, data, information about your location, questions, comments, suggestions or other content, such as Personal Information (collectively, “User Content”). We or others may store, display, reproduce, publish, distribute or otherwise use User Content online or offline in any media or format and may or may not attribute it to you. Others may have access to this User Content and may be able to share it with third parties. Please think carefully before sharing information with your User Content. We do not control who will have access to the information that you choose to make public. We can’t be sure that parties who have access to such information will respect your privacy or keep it secure. We are not responsible for the privacy or security of any information that you make publicly available on the Site or on the Program site. We are not responsible for what others do with information you share with them on the Site or on the Program site. We are not responsible for the accuracy, use or misuse of any User Content that you share or receive from third parties through the Site or the Program site. 
  * _Name and Likeness._ We may publish your name, voice, likeness and other Personal Information that is part of your User Content. We may use the content, or any part of the content, for advertising, marketing, publicity and promotional activities. For full terms and conditions about User Content you submit to the Site, please review the Site's Terms of Use. For full terms and conditions about User Content you submit to the Program site, please review our  Terms of Service. 

## Do we Collect Information about Children?

We are a general audience site. We do not knowingly collect, maintain, or use Personal Information on the Site about children under the age 13 that requires parental notice and consent under the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”). If you are a child under the age of 13, you are not permitted to use the Site and should not send any information about yourself to us through the Site. 

If we become aware that we have collected personal information from any child, we will dispose of that information in accordance with applicable law. If you are a parent or guardian and you believe that your child under the age of 13 has provided us with Personal Information without COPPA-required consent, please contact us. Our contact information is below. 

## How about Transfer of Information to the United States or other Countries?

The Site operates in the United States. The Site is meant for users located in the United States. We and our service providers may transfer, process, store, and use information we collect, in the United States, outside the United States, or both. The data protection laws in the United States and other countries may be different than those of the country in which you are located. Your personal information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in the United States and other countries according to laws of the United States, those countries, or both. By using the Site or giving us any information, you consent to the transfer, processing, usage, sharing and storage of your information in and outside the United States as described in this Privacy Policy. 

## OneMain Rewards Program.

OneMain offers the OneMain Rewards Program (the "Program"), which is operated by a third-party service provider for us. When you enter the Program site, you are leaving the Site and visiting a website that our service provider, CrowdTwist, operates. This Privacy Policy will continue to apply to your use of the Program site. Thus, when we use the terms "we," "us", or "our" in this Section, these terms include both OneMain and CrowdTwist. These notices apply to your participation in the Program, including any online service location you access when participating in the Program that posts or links to this Privacy Policy. These notices also apply to all features offered through the Program site. These notices apply regardless of how you access or use the Program site. 

If we give you notice through the Program site, or through other methods of communication, of different or additional privacy policies or practices, those terms will apply to that data collection and use. 

Please read the Program’s  Terms of Service which covers your participation and use of the Program.  _By using the Program site, you consent to this Privacy Policy and the_Terms of Service. _You also consent to our collection, use and sharing of your information and data, and other activities, as described below._

  *  _Information you Provide to us._ In connection with the Program, we may ask you to provide us and/or our third-party service providers with certain information, such as (1) Personal Information (as defined above) and (2) demographic information, such as information about your gender or age ("Demographic Information"). We may collect this information through many forms and in many places in the Program. For example, we may collect this information if you sign-up for the Program’s online account management function as required to enter the Program or when you otherwise interact with the Program. If we combine Demographic Information with the Personal Information we collect directly from you in connection with the Program or the Program site, we will treat the combined data as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy. 
  * _Information Collected and Stored as you Access and use the Program._ We and our third-party service providers may use technologies that store or collect certain information when you visit or interact with the Program site ("Program Usage Information"). This Program Usage Information may be stored or accessed using technologies that may be downloaded to your Device when you visit or interact with the Program site. This Program Usage Information may include: 
    * Your IP address, UDID or other unique identifier ("Program Device Identifier"). A Program Device Identifier is a number that is automatically assigned to your Device used to access the Program site. Our computers identify your Device by its Program Device Identifier.
    * Your Device functionality (such as browser, operating system, hardware, mobile network information).
    * The areas within the Program site that you visit and your activities there, such as remembering you, the frequency and duration of your use, and your preferences.
    * Your Device location.
    * Your Device characteristics.
    * Other Device data, such as the time of day, and the address of the website from which you entered the Program site, among other information.

We may use many methods and technologies to store or collect Program Usage Information such as Cookies and Web Beacons (collectively, "Tracking Technologies"). We may use other Tracking Technologies with the Program site. We may use Tracking Technologies for different purposes, such as: 

    * _Strictly Necessary._ We may use Tracking Technologies needed to let you use and access the Program site. This includes cookies required to prevent fraudulent activity, improve security or allow you to make use of point redemption functionality. 
    * _Performance Related._ We may use Tracking Technologies to assess the performance of the Program and the Program site. This includes using Tracking Technologies as part of our analytic practices and to improve the activities, content, products and services of the Program and the Program site. 
    * _Functionality Related._ We may use Tracking Technologies to give you better functionality when you use the Program site. This includes identifying you when you use the Program site and keeping track of your preferences, such as how content on the Program site is presented. 
    * _Targeting Related._ We may use Tracking Technologies to give you content relevant to your interests in the Program and third-party services based on how you use our content. This includes using Tracking Technologies to understand whether the content you get is useful. 
  * _Interactions with Third-Party Services._ The Program site may include functions that allow certain interactions between the Program site and a third-party web site or application. These functions may involve the third-party operator providing certain information to us, such as Personal Information. For example, after you sign-up for our online account management function needed to enter the Program, you may have a choice to link your Facebook, Instagram, Twitter, Foursquare or other account provided by a third-party site, platform or application to your Program account so that you may take part in certain types of Program point-earning activities that we may offer from time to time. If you choose to use this account-connecting function, the third-party site, platform or application may send Personal Information about you to us. We will then treat it as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy, since we are collecting it as a result of your accessing of and interaction on the Program. We may also provide third-party sites’ interfaces or links on the Program site to help send a communication from the Program site. For example, we may use third parties to facilitate emails, posts, check-ins, Tweets or Facebook postings. These third parties may keep any information used or provided in these communications or other activities. These third parties’ practices are not subject to our Privacy Policy. We may not control or have access to your communications through these third parties. When you use third-party sites or services, you are using their services and not our services. We are not responsible for their practices. You should review the third-party privacy policies before using such third-party tools on the Program site. 
  * _Information you Provide about a Third Party._ You may send someone a message from the Program site, such as an invitation to a friend. The information you provide (for example, names and email addresses) is used to aid the communication and is not used by us for any other marketing purpose unless we get consent from that person or we say otherwise. When you use the send-to-a-friend function on the Program site, your contact information, name or user name and message may be included in the communication sent to your addressee(s). Some of these tools may be third-party tools subject to third-party privacy policies. 
  * _How do we use the Information Collected in Connection with the Program?_

We may use your Personal Information, Demographic Information or Program Usage Information that is collected in connection with the Program: 

    * To process transactions or provide you with information such as to send you electronic newsletters or ads, such as to let you know about new products, services or upcoming events. 
    * To let you participate in different Program features like participating in online entry sweepstakes, contests or other point-earning activities or promotions and awarding points for your completed Program activities. 
    * To process your joining the Program, such as making sure your information is active and valid. 
    * To improve the Program, marketing endeavors or the Program offerings. 
    * To customize your experience with the Program and on the Program site or to show you content or ads that are relevant to you. 
    * To fulfill rewards you earned through the Program. 
    * To provide customer support. 
    * To help solve problems with the Program. 
    * To contact you about your use of the Program and about changes to the Program or Program’s policies or terms and conditions, including the Terms of Service. 
    * To identify your product and Program preferences so that you can learn about new or additional point-earning activities, services and promotions. 
    * To improve the overall experience with the Program. 
    * For internal business purposes. 
    * For purposes disclosed at the time you provide your information or as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy or our Privacy Notice. 
  * _Information Disclosed Publicly or to Others._ See **“What About Information I Disclose Publicly or to Others?”** above for information about use of your User Content by us and others. For full terms and conditions about User Content you submit to the Program, please review our Terms of Service. 
  * _When do we Share Information with Third Parties?_ A description of the types of parties with which we share your Personal Information is in our Privacy Notice. Also, we share non-Personal Information, such as aggregated user statistics, with third parties. We may share your Program Device Identifiers with third parties along with data related to you and your activities. We may also disclose and transfer all information: (i) to a future owner, co-owner or operator of the Site or Program or applicable database; or (ii) in connection with a merger, consolidation, restructuring, the sale of substantially all our interests and/or assets or other corporate change, such as, during the course of any due diligence process. We may also share the information we have collected about you as described in this Privacy Policy or in our Privacy Notice. 

OneMain Perks. 

One feature in the Program is OneMain Rewards Perks ("Perks"). A third party, Next Jump, Inc. (“Next Jump”), operates Perks. When you enter Perks site, you are leaving the Site and visiting a website that Next Jump owns and operates. When you use the Perks site, Next Jump may collect Personal Information and other data from you. It has its own policies and practices that apply to the Perks site. We are not responsible for how Next Jump collects or uses your information. Next Jump may be tracking you across many sites and may be sharing the results of that tracking with us or others. Next Jump has its own terms of service, privacy policy and other policies. Next Jump may ask you to agree to the same. We are not responsible for Next Jump policies or practices. Be sure to review available policies before submitting any Personal Information to or otherwise interact with a third party. Use caution on the Perks site. We also urge you to note when you leave the Site. We also urge you to review the third-party privacy policies of all third-party locations and exercise caution in connection with them. 

How about Changes to this Privacy Policy? 

We may change this Privacy Policy.  If we do, we will post the changed Privacy Policy on the Site. The ”Last Updated” date of this Privacy Policy is the last time we materially changed this Privacy Policy.  That date is at the top of this Privacy Policy. That date lets you know whether we made changes since the last time you reviewed this Privacy Policy.
